<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Myles' Website - Technology</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/technology.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-06-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Installing docker on Fedora 32</title><link href="/docker-configuration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Myles</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-06-12:/docker-configuration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;How to configure docker on a system running Fedora 32&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing the docker repos DO NOT have an entry for Fedora 32
.. raw:: html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have began learning docker. However upon attempting to install it, I ran into a few issues which resulted in me using an ubuntu server virtual machine, which was less than ideal
for what I was attempting. Below I will document what I did and how I solved the issues that I had ran into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;First off before we start installing anything new it's best to run an update first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo dnf -y update
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#safer to restart your system after&lt;/span&gt;
sudo shutdown -r now
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we want to add the docker repo, so that we can install the packages we want&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo dnf config-manager &lt;span class="se"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
--add-repo &lt;span class="se"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
https://download.docker.com/linux/fedora/docker-ce.repo
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we try to install docker-ce now, we get 404, as the repository does not contain entries for fedora 32 yet, we can opt to use the fedora 31
repos through the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo sed -i &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s/$releasever/31/g&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; /etc/yum.repos.d/docker-ce.repo
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with sed, all this does is goes through the entry yum/dnf has for the docker repo and replaces 32 with 31 -&amp;gt; hence we actually install packages from the fedora 31 repos.
Now we can install packages that we need from the docker repo, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo dnf install docker-ce
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we also want to enable the docker service, we can do this without rebooting using the now arguement. We additionally may want to add ourselves to the group docker so we can use docker commands without sudo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo systemctl &lt;span class="nb"&gt;enable&lt;/span&gt; --now docker
sudo usermod -aG docker &lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;whoami&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we try to create a new container with some arbitrary image, like so, we may get a final error regarding cgroups, Since fedora 31, the default setting is for cgroup V2 to before
enabled by default. (cgroups is a feature implemented in the kernel that allows for the isolation of resources to a collection of processes, clearly this is useful when utilising containers)#
sadly this isnt supported by docker yet (at the time of writing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;docker run --rm hello-world

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# probably some image pull stuff here&lt;/span&gt;

docker: Error response from daemon: cgroups: cannot found cgroup mount destination: unknown.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to fix this we can revert back to cgroups V1 on the next reboot by providing an arguement to the kernel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo dnf install grubby
sudo grubby --update-kernel&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;ALL --args&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;”systemd.unified_cgroup_hierarchy&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="m"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now after all that we should be able to get the hello world image to work with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;docker run --rm hello-world
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# this should work&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Technology"></category></entry></feed>